我觉得列车上的一些人忘了
I believe some folks on this train forget
威尔福德先生是多么慷慨了不起的人
just how generous and wonderful a man Mr. Wilford actually is.
我没有
Not me.
我永远不会忘记
I could never forget.
是威尔福德在运行我们神圣的引擎
It's Wilford who runs our Sacred Engine.
是威尔福德的手指摸着我们的脉搏
It's Wilford who has His finger on our pulse,
是他清楚地知道我们需要什么
who knows exactly what we need --
我们需要多少食物和水
how much food and water,
多少暖气和空间 多少纪律
how much heat and space, how much discipline.
是威尔福德让我们不必面临严寒
It's Wilford who saved us from the bitter Cold.
他是我们还活着的唯一原因
He's the only reason we're alive.
但不知为何 在这列我们称为家的火车上
Yet somehow, on this train we all call home,
还有些乘客认为他们可以挑战他
there are passengers who see fit to challenge Him,
这些乘客自以为更聪明
passengers who think they know better,
这些乘客不知道
passengers who take for granted
感激他赐予我们的伟大奇迹
this great miracle that He's given us.
口令
Password?
"吃了富人"
"Eat the Rich."
脱鞋 保持安静
Take off your shoes and keep quiet.
莱顿可没说我是要来见个孩子
Layton didn't tell me I'd be meeting a kid.
右边
On the right.
等等 你干什么
Wait. What are you doing?
站住 别过去
Stop! Don't go there!
回来
Get back here!
站住
Stop!
快点
Hurry up.
快来
Come on.
我去
Holy shit.
安静 他们能听到我们
Quiet. They can hear us.
威尔福德根本不在这里
There's no Wilford up here at all.
根本...
There --
威尔福德根本不在这里
There's no Wilford up here at all.
停下
Stop!
梅兰妮在操控一切
Melanie's running the whole thing.
莱顿想让你亲眼看到
Layton wanted you to see it for yourself.
他们会灭了她的
They're gonna tear her apart.
你可以走了
Now you can go.
我知道我总有一天能再见到威尔福德先生
One day, I know I'll see Mr. Wilford again.
到时 我会感谢他
And when I do, I will thank Him,
由衷感谢他所做的一切
from the bottom of my heart, for everything that He's done.
为我做的
For me.
为我们所有人做的
For all of us.
这是他的革命 1001节车厢的革命
These are His revolutions, 1,001 cars long.
雪国列车
第一季 第八集
好了 够了 起来 走
Okay. That's enough. Heads-up, move.
退后
Back it up now!
车尾 通讯部 附属列车 夜车
Tail, Comm, subtrain, Nightcar.
好 就是这样
Right, this is it.
一切都要靠我们在车中段跟守卫对峙
Everything hinges on us meeting the Jackboots mid-train,
就在这里
right here.
我们在自己的地盘上 打得他们难以招架
We hit them with overwhelming strength on our turf.
福爵家车厢的灯闪了
The lights just flashed in the Folgers' car.
小莱到车头了
LJ made it to the Engine.
好
All right.
行了 我们准备吧
This is it. Let's get ready.
-祝大家好运 -注意安全
- Good luck, everyone. - Stay safe.
莱顿 我不能确定司闸员会倒向哪一边
Layton, I can't say which side the Brakemen are gonna land.
你知道罗切多顽固
You know how stubborn Roche is.
我们都不想跟司闸员打 但
None of us wants a fight with the Brakemen, but...
今天肯定会有人死亡
there are gonna be casualties today.
你去哪了
Where have you been?
我无法解释
Look, I can't explain.
我需要你今天绝对别去三等厢
I just need you to stay out of Third today, okay?
为什么
Why?
你做了什么 贝丝
What did you do, Bess?
跟莱顿有关吗
Is this about Layton?
待在家里吧
Just stay home.
求你
Please.
我直截了当地问过你 你是不是在帮他
I asked you point blank whether you were helping him,
而你对我撒谎了
and you lied to my face?
珍珠
Jinju...
你为什么叫我远离梅兰妮·卡维尔
Why did you ask me to steer clear of Melanie Cavill?
因为你在招惹你不明白的麻烦
Because you're messing with things that you don't understand.
什么麻烦
What things?
你知道她把莱顿关进了抽屉 是吧
You knew she put Layton in a drawer, didn't you?
你在保护她
You're protecting her.
我在保护你 贝丝
I was protecting you, Bess.
你
You.
那你也知道
Did you also know...
她把一名车尾人折磨死了吗
she tortured a Tailie to death?
珍珠 我在想 你究竟知道这列火车
I wonder, Jinju, just how many deep, dark secrets
多少阴暗的机密
about this train you really do know.
请不要逼我在你和列车之间做选择
Please don't make me choose between you and the train.
今天就待在这里
Just stay in here today.
早安 罗伯特
Morning, Robert.
你是想商量周年庆典的事吗
You wanted to discuss the Anniversary celebrations?
请进 露丝
Please, come in, Ruth.
格雷指挥官
Commander Grey.
怎么了
What's going on?
露丝...
Ruth...
你要是有任何事想告知我们
if there's anything you need to tell us...
最好现在就说
best you do it now.
比如什么
Anything like what?
露丝 我们从火车头那听说了一件事 很是不安
Ruth, we've heard a rather disturbing account from the Engine.
不会吧 怎么了
Oh, no. What's going on?
据可靠消息
We've been told, reliably,
威尔福德先生并不在火车头
that Mr. Wilford is not in the Engine...
也不在这列火车上
nor anywhere else on this train.
有证据表明梅兰妮·卡维尔在掌管雪国列车
There's evidence that Melanie Cavill is running Snowpiercer.
你是在骗我吗
Are you having a go at me?
在水族馆让我难堪还不够吗
Embarrassing me in the Aquarium wasn't enough for you?
-露丝 -你是疯了吗 诺兰
- Ruthie... - Have you lost your mind, Nolan?
你明知威尔福德在火车头 你见过他
You know that Wilford's in the Engine. You've seen him.
你和他握过手
You've shaken the man's hand.
列车启程后就没见过了
Not since departure I haven't.
我们只想知道这是不是真的
We simply need to know if this is true.
如果是真的
Because if it is,
就必须有人来治理列车
someone needs to assert governance of this train.
比如说你吗 莱拉
Someone like you, Lilah?
露丝 你去召集头等厢委员会过来
Ruth, why don't you gather the First Class Committee?
我们会查个水落石出
We'll get to the bottom of this.
这是芝加哥
This is Chicago,
我们一天半后就会到那
and we should be there in a day and a half.
这是我们最慢的一圈 对不对
This is our slowest revolution, isn't it?
落后平均时长22小时
22 hours off average.
每转一圈速度都会慢一点
We lose a little bit of time each revolution.
所以这要靠我们来改变
So it's on us to reverse that.
因为一旦雪国列车停摆 我们都会丧命
Because if Snowpiercer stops, we all die.
没错
That's right.
梅兰妮
Melanie...
你女儿是什么样的
What was your daughter like?
她...
She was...
很聪明
smart.
和你一样
Like you.
贴心
Sweet.
比我友善得多
Much nicer than me.
她发生了什么
What happened to her?
她最后和我爸妈在一起
She was with my parents at the end.
艾莉本该和他们一起登上列车的
Allie was supposed to get on the train with them.
但是
But, uh...
她没上来
didn't make it.
我爸妈也没上来
My parents didn't make it, either.
但我有车尾妈妈 乔茜
But I have my Tail mom, Josie.
梅 头等厢有急事找你
Mel. You're needed in First urgently.
好 你来盯着
Okay, you're on lookout.
发现异常情况 就告诉哈维或者班尼特
If you see anything, tell Javi or Bennett.
没问题
Okay.
不好意思
Excuse me.
是有什么问题吗
Is there a problem?
有一件极具煽动性的事需要我们澄清
There's something rather incendiary that we need cleared up.
什么事
What is it?
传闻威尔福德先生不在列车上
There's been a report that Mr. Wilford is not aboard the train.
太荒谬了
Well, that's ridiculous.
我昨晚就见了他
I met with him last night.
那恐怕得让威尔福德先生自己来证明
Well, I'm afraid we need Mr. Wilford to prove it himself.
亲自出面
In person.
好吧
All right.
那我去打电话
Well, I'll get the phone,
莱拉 你来和他通话
and, Lilah, you can talk to him yourself.
这次行不通了 梅兰妮
That isn't going to work this time, Melanie.
我们知道你掌管着雪国列车
We know you're running Snowpiercer.
我们有目击证人作证
We have an eyewitness account.
从火车头传来的
Direct from the Engine.
是谁
From whom?
没开玩笑吧
Seriously?
你们居然相信她
You're listening to her?
火车头和我想的不太一样
It's not what I was expecting, the Engine.
根本不是什么永动机
Not eternal at all.
更像是鼠巢
More like a rat's nest,
靠橡皮筋和电线固定在一起
held together with rubber bands and wires.
凭什么要听你说的 小莱
And why should anyone believe you, LJ?
没错 她就是个疯子
Exactly, she's a psycho,
-我们居然还... -放肆
- and we're putting... - How dare you!
我看到了她的住处
I saw her quarters!
我看到了她的书和地图
I saw her books, her maps,
包括她死去可怜女儿的照片
and even this photo of her poor, dead daughter.
但是却没有威尔福德先生
No Mr. Wilford, though!
放开我
Let me go!
退下
Back off!
他有枪
He's got a gun!
打给所有可行动的小队
Call all available units!
指挥官 你不能打电话
Commander, you can't!
我们需要那些小队待在后车厢
We need those units downtrain.
我不再听命于你
I don't take orders from you anymore.
车尾守卫
Tail Station.
收到
Roger that.
头等厢有罪案发生
Got a 10-10 up in First.
出什么事了
What's going on?
我不知道
I don't know.
加派人手巡逻
Double up patrols.
早日回归 小子们
Come back again soon, boys!
行动
Do it.
守卫正赶往前车厢
The Jackboots are headed uptrain.
你准备好了 吗
You ready for this?
现在不能反悔了
No going back now.
发出信号
Send out the signal.
抱歉 我必须要走了
Sorry, I must get going.
看起来不错
Looks good.
各位 我们的废料快用完了
Guys, we're running out of scrap.
如果我们限量配给水
If we ration the water,
也许可以拆卸掉几个水桶
maybe we can strip a couple water barrels down.
我们现在孤注一掷 去拆吧
We're all-in now. Do it.
我们需要任何可以用来做武器的东西
We need everything we have for weapons.
不好意思 各位 借过
Excuse me, guys! Comin' through!
我收到一条信息
I got a message.
革命
Revolución.
今天发动
We go today.
把消息散播出去
Spread the word.
囚犯来了
Prisoner coming through.
做得好 司闸员
Nice work, Brakeman.
除非迫不得已 否则我不想动粗
I don't want to rough you up unless I have to.
看着我的嘴
Read my lips.
在有进一步通知前 大家要待在各自的住处
Until further notice, you're all confined to quarters.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你无权这么做
You don't have the authority to do that.
闭嘴 年轻人
Shut your mouth, boyo.
把她关起来
Lock her up.
你这么做是错的
You're making a mistake.
露丝 这么做不对
Ruth, it's a mistake!
诺兰 如果我们做错了呢
Nolan, what if we're wrong about this?
如果威尔福德在火车头呢 这是叛乱
What if Wilford is in the Engine? This is mutiny.
那我们要亲自去看看 露丝
Then we need to see for ourselves, Ruthie.
你和我去火车头
You and I to the Engine.
万圣节快乐
Happy Halloween.
快一点
Make it fast.
我觉得戴这面具像个傻蛋
I feel like a dizhiv wanker in this.
大约翰 这是杰克斯
Big John, this is Jakes.
这些是莱顿最厉害的车尾人吗
These are Layton's best Tailies?
我们现在同一阵线
Hey, same side now.
把约翰带过去
Take John down.
他的人会把你需要的零件拿给你的
His people will bring the parts you need.
莱茨 你跟我走
Lights, you stick with me.
我的人呢
Where's my guy?
我在这里
I'm right here.
真没想到
Streuth.
可以走了吗
Shall we?
泰森
Tyson.
你知道这个命令是不合法的
You know these aren't lawful orders.
坐下
Sit down.
他们拿走的我女儿的照片
That photo that they took of my daughter,
我在车厢里还有一张 能让我去拿吗
I have another one in the booth, if you let me get it.
不行
Can't do that.
只是...
It's just...
如果我有什么事
if something happens to me...
我希望有她在身边
I want her close.
快去快回
Quickly.
梅要我们封锁火车头
Mel wants us to lock down the Engine.
为什么要封锁起来
What would you lock down for?
不如你跟我们说说吧 孩子
Why don't you tell us, kid?
才来两天 就要进入封锁状态吗
Two days here and we're already into lockdown?
怎么回事
What was that?
去看看大门
Hit the door.
本
Ben.
本 他们会杀了我们的 完了
Ben, they're gonna kill us. It's over.
封锁火车头 哈维
Lock it down, Javi!
我们为什么不打开门 告诉他们真相呢
Why don't we just open the door and tell them the truth?
-他们需要我们 -快去
- They need us. - Do it now!
-不要 -快去
- Come on! - Now!
进来
Go!
-你做了什么 -我必须这样做
- What'd you do? - I had to.
-你做了什么 -抱歉
- What'd you do? - I'm sorry.
不不不
No, no, no!
本 本 本 本 不要
Ben! Ben, Ben, Ben, Ben, Ben, please!
妈的
Shit!
抓住他
Grab him!
好的 好的 好的
All right, all right, all right!
威尔福德在哪
Where is Wilford?
他死了
He's dead.
把他铐起来
Cuff him.
他在出发日那天就死了
He's been dead since departure.
梅兰妮接管了列车 我什么都没有参与
Melanie took the train. I had nothing to do with it.
你得相信我
You have to believe me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
把他带走
Take him away.
你还好吗
You all right?
威尔福德死了 诺兰
Wilford is dead, Nolan.
他已经死了很多年
He's been dead for years...
没有人知道
and no one even knew.
这么长时间... 我怎么会没发觉
All that time... how did I not know?
这是什么 我是说...
And what is this? I mean...
这一切都是什么
What is all of this?
她欺骗了我们所有人 露丝
She deceived us all, Ruth.
现在人们还能指望什么
What will people hold onto now?
你
You.
我
Me.
秩序
Order.
我要让她付出代价 诺兰
I want her to pay, Nolan.
我要让她付出代价
I want her to pay.
我们为什么要加强巡逻
So, why are we doubling up our patrols?
-我不知道 但最好是有要事 -沃特
- I don't know, but it better be something good. - Walter.
你来迟了
You're late.
这是莱茨
This is Lights.
她和你一起
She's with you.
电气室
你终于抓到告密者了吗
You finally caught the Rat?
怎么了
What?
他在反抗 不是吗
He was resisting, wasn't he?
把门打开
Just open the doors.
我得询问一下前车
I gotta check this uptrain.
就是这了 后方通信线路
Here it is -- rear comms --
不不不不 你得找到50/125
No, no. No, no, no, no. You gotta look for 50/125 --
可是没有50/125
There is no 50/125!
我是驻扎车尾的杰弗森
This is Jefferson in Tail station.
我们没时间找了 我现在就得拉
We don't have time for this. I'm just gonna pull.
怎么
What the --
混蛋
Asshole.
武装起来
Weapons up!
我就知道你会回来找我们的
Sabía que volverías por nosotros.
今天出去散步不错吧 里格斯先生
Nice day for a walk, Mr. Riggs?
是的 孩子
Yes, it is, son.
让我们散步散得久一点
Let's make it a long one.
她怎么也在这儿
Why is she here?
大家听着
Listen up.
提尔现在是我们的人了
Till is one of us now.
听着 我知道你们很难去信任他人
Look, I know y'all got trust issues.
我也是
I got 'em, too.
前车的人们
People uptrain,
他们把我们扔在这黑暗里 让我们自生自灭
they shoved us down here in the dark to fend for ourselves.
我们学会了如何在暗影里生存
We learned how to survive in the shadows.
是的 是的
Yeah! Yeah!
今天...
Well, today...
今天 让我们离开这个地狱
today, let's leave this hell behind!
我们会用我们所拥有的一切进行斗争
We will fight with everything we got.
因为就在那边 那扇门外面
'Cause out there, right outside that door,
那边世界的未来不接受我们
there is a future that does not include us!
但它会接受的
But it will.
今天 我们将接管这列车
Today, we take this train
我们将提醒他们 他们锁在这车尾里的
and we remind them exactly who it is
到底是怎样一群人
that they locked up back here!
今天 我们要为乔茜游行
Today, we march for Josie!
为乔茜
For Josie!
为苏珊
For Suzanne!
为苏珊 为老伊凡
For Suzanne, for Old Ivan!
老伊凡
Old Ivan!
为了我们每一个因饥饿和疾病
For everyone that we have lost to hunger and to sickness,
以及因为失败叛乱而逝去的人
to all the failed rebellions.
有人愿意为我们牺牲生命
We got people who are willing to lay down their lives for us
因为他们相信 就如同我们深知
because they believe, like we know,
是时候让这趟列车
that it is time for this train
为所有乘客服务了
to work for all of its passengers!
今天
Today...
我们向火车头进军
we march to the Engine!
车尾一心
One Tail!
不
No.
列车一心
One Train.
One Train!
-列车一心 -列车一心
- One Train! - One Train!
好了 走吧 越快越好
All right, let's go. Fast as you can.
大约翰在等着呢
Big John's waiting.
列车一心
One Train!
电气室
沃特 你要去哪
Walter. Where you off to?
我回了电气室
I'm -- I'm back in electrics.
她刚给我看了点东西
She was showing me a few things.
我操 她是车尾人
No, shit -- she's a Tailie!
不
Oh, no! Hey, hey!
呼叫前列车厢
Hey, call forward!
让格雷指挥官派守卫来这里
Tell Commander Grey to get his Jackboots back here fast!
放开我
Get off me!
奥斯维勒 线路不通
Osweiller, the line's dead.
你到底想干什么
What the hell are you up to?
好吧 走过去 快
All right, go on foot! Go now!
这是莱顿必须遵守的重要诺言
This is a very important promise Layton needs to keep.
你明白吧 默里
You understand that, don't you, Murray?
当然 他们是我的朋友
Yeah, they're me mates.
已经很久没人叫过我默里了
No one's called me Murray in ages.
亨利 这位是默里
Henry, this is Murray.
-你好 -他看起来可不像车尾人
- Hey. - He doesn't look like a Tailie.
你看起来也不像医生
Well, you don't look like much of a doctor.
你准备好了吗 我需要你的帮助
Are you ready? I-I'm gonna need your help.
我的天
Christ almighty.
我为你自豪 亨利
I'm proud of you, Henry.
我知道你会作出正确的选择
I knew you'd do the right thing.
谢谢 是时候了
Thank you. It's about time.
那就开始吧
Well, go on, then.
大力士
Strong Boy...
你这丑货
you ugly bugger.
需要先由我们三人
The passengers need to be told the news
把消息告诉乘客
from the three of us first.
让他们立刻知道谁才是是管事的
Let them know immediately who is in charge.
我去开门
I'll get it.
指挥官
Commander!
指挥官 列车后方出事了
Commander. There's trouble downtrain.
通讯系统瘫痪了 车尾人闯出来了
Comms are down, and there are Tailies out.
车尾人
The Tailies?
就在我们为威尔福德争吵的时候
While we squabbled over Wilford up here.
这可不是巧合
That's no bloody coincidence.
所有小队 去列车后方
All units -- downtrain now!
走隧道最快
The tunnels are the fastest access.
跑步前进
Double time!
快走
Let's go! Go!
露丝
Ruth...
别说话
Please don't talk.
不管你现在对我有什么看法
Whatever you think of me right now,
请先放到一边
please put it aside --
我要你别讲话
I need you not to talk.
所有这些我们的回忆
All these memories I have of us...
那些我以为是真实的时刻
Moments that, uh, I took to be true...
一起吃饭
From sharing a meal together,
在委员会会议上站一整个通宵
on our feet during an all-night committee meeting...
扮演好警察坏警察解决头等厢的争端
playing good-cop bad-cop to settle squabbles in First.
还有当你给我
Or when you gave me
威尔福德先生对我的个人表彰
my personal commendation from Mr. Wilford...
表彰我对公司的杰出贡献
For my outstanding dedication to the company...
这是你应得的
You earned that.
这么多年来
All those years...
你是不是一直在嘲笑我
were you just laughing at me?
你把我耍得团团转
Hey? You made a fool of me.
一遍又一遍
Over and over.
我们的友谊是真的
The friendship was real.
你杀了他吗 梅兰妮
Did you kill Him, Melanie?
威尔福德不是你想的那样 露丝
Wilford wasn't who you thought He was, Ruth.
他是骗子
He was a fraud.
他打造了永动机
He built the Eternal Engine.
不 他没有
No, He didn't.
是我
I did.
我造了这辆列车 露丝
I built this train, Ruth.
我投入了我的一切
I put everything I had into it.
一切
Everything.
威尔福德只是卖票的
And Wilford sold tickets.
他不相信我们能拯救人类
He didn't believe it was possible to save humankind.
他根本没打算尝试
And He was never even going to try.
-那不是真的 -他想要挥霍掉一切
- That's not true. - He was going to waste it!
他只想要尽可能活得好
All He wanted was to live as well as He could,
尽可能活得久
for as long as He could,
被赞誉包围
surrounded by accolades and...
还有酒精和夜车里的妓女
booze and whores in the Nightcar.
要是他管理的话 我们连一圈都走不完
We wouldn't have made it one revolution.
于是我接管了雪国列车
So I took Snowpiercer...
我把他扔到轨道旁等死
and I left Him trackside to die.
抱歉我骗了你
I'm sorry I lied to you.
抱歉
I'm sorry for...
我做过的所有错事
all the things that I did wrong.
我一直在努力做我认为正确的事
I've been fighting to do what I know is right.
你个卑劣的骗子
You're a filthy liar.
还是杀人犯
And a murderer.
秩序会恢复
Order will be restored.
明天 你会因为背叛雪国列车
Tomorrow, you will be executed
而被处决
for your betrayal of Snowpiercer.
再见 梅兰妮
Goodbye, Melanie.
列车一心
One Train!
莱顿 守卫过来了
Layton! Jackboots on the move.
我们得快点
We gotta hurry.
等等 还没说完
Wait. There's more.
司闸员在链条里集合
The Brakemen are forming up in The Chains.
该死 罗切
Shit. Roche...
列车一心
One Train!
-我们走 -列车一心
- Let's go! - One Train!
见鬼 老大 我们等支援吧
Bloody hell, Boss. Let's wait for backup.
守卫就要来了
Jackboots are on their way.
成熟点 奥斯维勒
Get your big-boy pants on, Osweiller.
我们就在这里挡下暴民
We're gonna hold this mob right here.
他们有400余人
There's must be about 400 of them.
你没危险啊
Well, good thing for you
这些年你一直对他们很好 不是吗
you've been so nice to them over the years, then, isn't it?
列车一心
One Train!
-列车一心 -只有我们 罗切
- One Train! - It's just us, Roche.
行了 别再靠近了
All right, that's far enough.
你真是让我失望 司闸员
You are of great disappointment to me, Brakeman.
我猜到了
Yeah, I figured I would be.
在中间讨好两边的人 对吗
Right in the middle of it, weren't ya?
你一直参与其中
The whole bleeding time.
我选了边
I picked a side.
我们不是来和你打的 罗切
Look, we're not here to fight you, Roche.
我们只需要通过
We just need to pass through.
不 你和你的车尾朋友哪都别想去
No, you and your Tail friends, you're not going anywhere.
更别想通过这里
You're certainly not going through here.
车尾不是敌人
The Tail's not the enemy.
屁才不是 听到了没
The hell they aren't! You hear that?
他们想要拆散这里
They want to tear this place apart.
我们反抗的对象不是三等厢 罗切
Our fight is not with Third, Roche.
你该让这些平民回家
You should've sent all these civilians home.
不 我可不这么认为
No, see, I don't think so.
因为这里没人会相信
'Cause nobody here is gonna believe
你说给他们的谎言
any of the lies you're selling them.
威尔福德死了 那算什么
Wilford's dead? What is that?
某种心理战吗
Some kind of psychological warfare?
不 那是真的 老大 他没骗人
No, it's true, Boss. He's not lying.
梅兰妮把他放进了抽屉 就因为他看穿了
Melanie threw him in a Drawer because he figured it out.
听着
Listen.
如果你们想 你们可以相信传说
You can believe the myth if you want.
事实是
The fact is,
头等厢也刚刚得知真相
First just learned the truth, too.
有人得接管这辆列车
Now, somebody is going to take over this train.
你是希望他们接管还是我们
Would you rather it be them or us?
三等厢和车尾一起
Third and the Tail together.
反正也一直是我们在保持列车的运行 对吗
We're the ones who've been keeping this train running anyway, right?
列车一心
One Train!
听着 罗切 我知道这不是你的选择
Look, Roche, I know you didn't choose this.
把人关在漆黑的笼子里 挨饿
Locking people up in cages, in the dark, starving?
那不是你
That's not you.
你是个好警察
You are a good cop.
做出正确的选择 让开
Make the right choice. Just move aside.
等这事结束后
You're gonna need all the Brakemen
你会需要所有司闸员来维持秩序
to keep the order when this is done.
拜托 老大
Come on, Boss.
想想安妮
Think of Anne.
想想你女儿
Think of your daughter.
不管了
Balls to this, man.
奥斯维勒 守住防线
Osweiller, hold the line.
这制服可不会保护我不被他们攻击
This uniform's not gonna protect me from that lot.
-我要照顾自己 -不准走
- I'll look after myself. - Stay in line!
回来
Get back in line!
该死 提尔
God damn it, Till.
现在我得回家告诉我妻子 威尔福德不在了吗
Now I have to go home and tell my wife there's no Wilford?
站一边去 司闸员
Stand aside, Brakemen.
-快 快把他弄醒 -需要时间
- Come on. Get him up faster. - It takes time.
-要是唤醒太快 -会怎样
- If I bring them out too quickly -- - What?
耐心点 拜托
Just be patient! Please.
什么情况 怎么了 帮帮我
What the hell, man? What is -- Help me.
那是什么 普通话吗
What's that? Mandarin?
他会说普通话吗
Does he speak Mandarin?
不
No.
他是哑巴
He doesn't speak.
什么
What?
接到报告 长官 小队都准备就绪了
Got a report in, sir. Units here and ready.
很好 叫他们行动起来
Good, son. Keep 'em moving.
快 快 拿上盾牌出发
Let's move! Let's move! Grab a shield and go!
跑步前进 守卫 跑步前进
Double time, Jacks! Double time!
很好 快
That's it! Let's go!
战士们上前
Fighters come forward!
我需要所有战士跟我到前面去
I need all the fighters up front with me!
快 我们得快点
Let's go. We gotta go.
你可以的
You got this.
快点 快点
Come on, hurry up! Hurry up!
他们马上就来了
They'll be here any second.
块
Quickly!
我能听到他们 我能听到他们
I can hear 'em. I can hear 'em.
守卫 他们来了
Jackboots! They're coming!
快 准备就位
Move! Get into position!
好的 稳住
Okay, hold.
稳住
Hold.
快了
Almost.
好
Okay.
现在 发射
Now! Firing!
找掩护
Take cover!
快 装弹 装弹
Let's go! Reload, reload!
冲
Advance!
快 快 快 快
Let's go, let's go, let's go, let's go!
第二轮 第二轮
Second round! Second round!
现在
Now!
很好
Yes!
现在怎么办 指挥官
What now, Commander?
你们继续施压
You keep pressing.
我要从上面绕道 从背后攻击他们
I'm gonna double back up top, hit 'em in the arse.
你的人 跟我来
Your men, with me!
冲 冲
Advance! Advance!
准备
Clear it, clear it!
现在
Now!
连接
格雷
Grey!
进攻
Attack!
守住
Hold the line!
弓箭手 干掉前线
Archers, take out the front line!
提尔 他们在走楼梯 帮我们盯住后面
Till, they're taking the stairs. Watch our backs.
提尔 小心后面
Till, behind you!
撤退
Retreat!
Fall back!
撤退
Retreat!
格雷
Grey!
撤退
Retreat!
快 快
Go, go, go!
撤退
Retreat!
快 快
Go, go, go! Go!
他们来了
Here they come!
这是最后一轮了
This is the last reload.
没了 弹药没了
That's it. Out of ammo.
撤退到下一道防线
Fall back to the next barricade.
我给你们争取点时间
I'll buy you some time.
拿上武器 快 快走
Take the weapon. Do it! Go!
你听到了 往后拉
You heard him! Pull it back!
现在是我们的机会 快
Now's our chance! Go, go, go!
快
Go!
列车一心
One Train.
我们做到了
We did it.
他们逃了
We have them on their heels.
继续紧逼
Let's keep pressing.
叫大家起来
Get everybody up.
好
Yeah.
莱顿 我们得走了
Layton, we have to move.
好样的 我们走
Well done. Let's go.
时刻准备好
Stay ready.
我们要朝前进发
We're pushing forward.
我们走 各位
Let's go, guys.
准备好了吗
Ready?
拿上武器
Gather their weapons!
尽可能拿多点
Get everything you can.
前面还有很长的路
We got a long march ahead of us.
退后
Get back!
退后 大家退后
Get back! Everybody back!
快 快
Let's go, let's go!
退后 快
Back now! Let's go!
快点 快 快
Come on, come on, come on! Let's go!
快走 快走
Move! Move, move!
撤退
Fall back!
不要停
Keep moving.
所有人都到了
That's the last of them.
前门关了 封住
Forward doors are closed. Seal it up.
莱顿 莱顿
Layton. Layton.
后备屏障暂时挡住了他们
Fallback barriers are holding for now.
大约翰呢
Big John?
他没能坚持下来
He didn't make it.
守住 继续补给
Hold the line and resupply.
听我指令 我们冲垮他们最后的防线
On my orders, we overrun their last defenses.
你的人呢
Where are your people?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们 我们应该先离开
We -- We -- We should just come back for the other sleepers,
晚点再唤醒沉睡者
wake them up later.
不 离开的话 我们就成囚犯了
No, we leave here and we're prisoners.
继续唤醒
We keep going.
钥匙给我
Give me the keys.
下一个是谁
Who's next?
派克
Pike.
你了解安德烈·莱顿
You have insight into Andre Layton?
是的
Oh, yeah.
我和莱顿很熟
I know Layton intimately.
他的政见总是正义凛然
Always so righteous with his politics.
我的对他来说从来不够优雅
Mine were never refined enough for him.
但是
But...
再给我一块这个
for another piece of this...
我就告诉你莱顿的秘密
...I'll give you Layton.
莱顿的问题是
The thing about Layton...
他是理想主义者
is he's an idealist.
一个好警察
A good cop.
受不了持续的残酷
Doesn't have the stomach for sustained cruelty.
他今天冒了巨大风险
He took a big risk today.
然后输了
And he lost.
继续耗下去
Keep grinding.
他会崩溃的
He'll crumble.